Register of the Allied and Associated Powers (1914-1920) Inter-Allied Food Council, 1917-1919
Hoover Institution Archives
Allied and Associated Powers (1914-1920) Inter-Allied Food Council,
1917-1919
XX008
Allied and Associated Powers (1914-1920) Inter-Allied Food Council
21 manuscript boxes (8.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Minutes of meetings, reports, correspondence, and statistics, relating to the coordination of Allied food supply and regulation during World War I.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Food supply.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1914-1918--Food question.
Container List
- CONTAINER LIST
  - Inter-Allied Scientific Food Commission (Commission Scientifique Inter-alliee du Ravitaillement: C.S.I.R.) (Box 1.)
  - Proces-Verbal de la Seance du 29, 30 April 1918 and 1, 2, 3, 4 & 6 May 1918
  - Proces-Verbal des Seances 22, 23 Bruxelles (May, 1918) Resolution et Projet de Convention relatifs a la Creation d'une Commission Scientifique International de l'Alimentation, Bruxelles, May 1919
  - Rapport General: Les Resources et les Besoins Alimentaires des Pays Allies
    - Premier Rapport Paris - July 1918
    - Premier Rapport (avec Annexes). Approuve par la Commission. Paris - Oct. 1919 (some annexes in English)
    - Troisieme Rapport (with annexes). Approuve par la Commission. Rome - Dec. 1918
  - Proces-Verbal de la Seance 3-8, 10-13 June 1918 (Box 2.)
  - Proces-Verbal de la Seance du 25-29 March 1918, et texts des resolutions adoptees. Reunion de cloture de la Conference le 30 March 1918
  - Proces-Verbal de la Seance 14-19, 22, 23 Oct. 1918 (Box 3.)
  - Rapport Sommaire des travaux de la C.S.I.R. reunie a Paris du 14-23 October 1918, presente par le Dr. Kellogg
  - Provisional Report of the Proceedings of the Commission at their meeting held in Paris from 14-23 Oct. 1918 (English/French)
  - Report of the Proceedings of the Commission at their meeting held in Paris from 14-23 Oct. 1918 (English/French)
  - Proces-Verbal de la Seance du 10, 11, 12, 14 Dec. 1918
    - Memorandum report on the meeting held at Rome and Naples, Dec. 9-14, 1918, by L. B. Mendel and H. P. Armsby of the American Delegation
    - Provisional Report of the 5th Session held at Rome and Naples, Dec. 9-14, 1918, drawn up by Professor E. H. Starling (English/French)
    - Copies of the General Reports of the First Report (Paris, October 1918) and Second Report, Rome, December 1918
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 4.)
  - Statistics
  - International Food Control
  - Agreements
  - Finance
  - Inter-Allied Council on War Purchases and Finance
  - C.S.I.R. (Box 5.)
  - France
  - Great Britain
  - Italy
  - United States
  - Belgium
  - Inter-Allied Tin Executive
  - Military Board of Allied Supply
  - Wheat Executive. Minutes of Proceedings
  - VIII Nov. - Dec. 1917
  - IX Feb. - Mar. 1918
  - XI May - June 1918
  - XXII July - Aug. 1919
  - Royal Commission on Wheat Supplies. Statement Tables 82, 83 (13, 20 July 1918), etc.
  - Royal Commission on Sugar Supplies
  - Sugar Programme Commission
  - Royal Commission on Wheat Supplies. Purchases (Box 6.)
  - Committee of the Wheat Executive. Minutes of meetings (March - August 1918). Incomplete
  - Purchasing Committee. Weekly Report (14 Sept. 1918 - 31 May 1919)
  - War Missions Board
  - Royal Commission on Wheat Supplies. Miscellaneous
  - Wheat Executive
  - Minutes of Proceedings, 1-22 Dec. 1916 - August 1919 (more details on folder)
  - Minutes, 7 November 1917 - 28 July 1919 (Multigraphs) Incomplete (Box 7.)
  - Minutes, miscellaneous loose
  - Finance Committee
  - Tables No. R.A., 15 March 1918 - 17 May 1919 (R.A., R.A.F., R.A.G., R.A.I., R.A.L., R.A.U.K.) (Box 8.)
  - Tables - miscellaneous
  - Tables - miscellaneous 1917-1919
  - Freight Commission. Minutes of meetings, 3 April - 28 August 1918 (Box 9.)
  - Series of "Weekly Reports on Labor Conditions" (Requested by War Department and War Industries Board, 1918-1919)
  - London Conference of Food Controllers. July - August 1918. (Box 10.)
  - Minutes (not complete) of Meetings
    - July 24, 26, 29, 30, 1918
    - August 12, 13, 1918
    - Inter-Allied Food Council (I.F.C.). Committee of Representatives. Minutes of Proceedings. I-IV, July - Dec. 1918 (91 pieces)
  - Dups of the following: (Box 11.)
  - Inter-Allied Scientific Food Commission
  - Inter-Allied Food Council. Committee of Representatives
  - P.T.L. (Provisions to Load) Tables 1-24
  - I.F.C. (Box 12.)
  - Committee of Representatives
    - Agenda, Minutes and Documents. September - December 1918
    - Freight Committee. Minutes and Agenda. September 1918 / January - February 1919
  - Food Controllers Conference. Miscellaneous Tables I.F.C. (Box 13.)
  - Committee of Representatives
    - R.A.F. Tables (1918)
    - Purchase Commission (Box 14.)
    - Recovered Territories Commission
    - Statistical Council
  - Meats Executive Committee
  - Oil Seed Committee
  - Inter-Allied Munitions Council (small areas committee) (Box 15.)
  - Inter-Allied Wheat Executive Commission (4 folders)
  - General
  - General (Box 16.)
  - Freight Committee
  - Freight Committee (Box 17.)
  - Inter-Allied Scientific Food Commission
  - Provisional Report, 9-14 December 1918
  - Set of Minutes for Meetings of Scientific Food Commission, May - June 1918
  - Inter-Allied Council on Armaments and Munitions. A.E.F. Reports, etc., 1918
  - I.F.C. Committee of Representatives. Freight Committee. Minutes October - December 1918; January - March 1919 (Box 18.)
  - Skinner, J. H. - correspondence with Herbert Hooover, etc. March - September 1918. (Skinner was the U.S. Food Administration Representative on the Inter-Allied Council for War Purchases and Finance.)
  - Miscellaneous letters, memos (State Department, re German capitulation, reconstruction plans, etc.)
  - U.S.F.A.
    - Report on department "Manche" and "Cotes du Nord" (Simpson), 13 July 1918
    - Report on department "Isere, Rhone, and Loire" 1 July 1918
  - Miscellaneous I.F.C. Committee of Representatives
    - Agenda
    - Resolutions
  - Memo relating to Inter-Allied Organizations (19 June 1918) 5 pages
  - Memorandum, "Allied Cereal Supplies and Requirements," 13 May 1917
  - Miscellaneous memos on grain exports
    - Herbert Hoover, drafts on Allied Wheat Commission
    - Exports Council
    - Cereal supplies (9, 11, 12 May 1917)
    - Untitled memo: "The food problem in U.S...." 6 May 1917 (12 pages)
  - Food Controllers Conference (Box 19.)
  - Minutes and Documents. 24, 26, 29, 30 July; 12, 13 August, 1918 (37 pieces)
  - Note sur le ravitaillement francaise. London. July 1918.
  - Plan for Supply of Cereals to France (1917 -1918)
  - Complementary note 1918. E. Vilgrain
  - Miscellaneous French material
  - I.F.C.
  - Resolutions, cables, etc. 1917-1918
  - Committee of Repesentatives. Statistical tables
  - Consumer's Council. Meeting held at Palace Chambers Westminster. 24 July 1918. Minutes of proceedings and reports (July - December 1918)
  - I.F.C. Addresses and Personnel
  - "Paris. Agricultural Conference. March 1919" Subject of cable (U.S.F.A. #425) 20 February 1919
  - Commission Internationale d'Alimentation (30 pieces) (Box 20.)
  - Inter-Allied Agricultural Conference. Paris. 11-14 February 1919 (71 pieces)
  - Allied Maritime Transport Council (Part I, 1918 and Part II, November 1918-April 1919)
  - Inter-Allied Oil Seeds Executive
  - Miscellaneous (185 pieces)
  - Minutes of Proceedings 1-23 (26 July 1918 - January 1919)
  - Resolutions passed by an Advisory Conference called by the Inter-Allied Oil Seeds Executives (December 7-11, 1918)
  - Allied Maritime Transport Council (235 pieces)
  - Allied Maritime Transport Executive
  - Rapport de la Delegation francaise de la C.S.I.R. sur la situation Alimentaure & L'etat sanitaire du nord de la France (4 pages) Paris, 20 Nov. 1918